<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	>
<channel>
  <title>Meditations on Unity is a Divided World</title>
  <link>https://wrhett.net/medidations/</link>
  <description>A collection of meditations by W. Rhett Davis</description>
  <language>en-US</language>
  <item>
    <title>A Humble Introduction</title>
    <link>https://wrhett.net/medidations/introduction.html</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 2 Jan 2023</pubDate>
    <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
    <description><![CDATA[Why do we need another media feed?  Here's why this one was created.]]></description>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="style1">Welcome to my media feed, dear reader. I hope that you will find your time here worthwhile.  I hope that together we can make sense of this strange and beautiful world in spite of our weaknesses and the forces that constantly try to drag us down.</p>
<p class="style1">One of the most effective tactics used to drag us down is division.  There is incredible power in unity.  Just look at the birth of our country!  In a world where autocracy seems to have been the norm throughout history, somehow a representative democracy took root and still shines as an inspiration to the world.  It would never have happened if our ancestors had not been unified in their purpose.</p>
<p class="style1">I want to do what I can to help lift you up when you feel down.  Since I may not have a chance to know you well, that means trying to connect you to the things that lift me up.  It also means standing firmly against the things that try to keep us both down.  So, I am putting this message in a bottle, hoping that it may find you and brighten your day and give you courage to face what lies ahead.  Unity is one of my favorite topics, probably because I am an identical twin and my parents were divorced.  But unity will not be the only topic.</p>
<p class="style1">If I ever say something that upsets or depresses you, I hope that you will let me know.  I would like the chance to apologize and learn how to avoid it in the future.  Or, if you have your own rush of inspiration, I would love to hear what lifts you up, too.  I may even figure out how to add your comments to this feed one day.  I won't leave my email address here, but you are resourceful.  I am sure that you will find me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
